# 你看
Look!
# 很多這個花哦
There are a lot of these flowers.
# 這個可以吃的 這個 果實可以吃的
These are edible. I mean, the fruits are edible.
# 現在還沒熟 熟了時候再來
Now they're still green. Let's come again when they're ripe.
# XXX啊 我們這邊叫 (註︰沒有原字幕)
We call them "o angzi" here.
# 哇 好多蕉芋花呀
Wa! A lot of Indian shots!
# 今天又不是情人節
But today is not the Valentine's Day.
# 這裡 有一個
Here, here's one.
# 好甜吶
So sweet!
# 這裡好多這蕉芋花 都沒人吃
Here are many this kind of Indian shots. But nobody wants them,
# 就我吃
except me.
# 現在
Now,
# 年輕人都不在家 (註︰這個「家」是指「老家」，說明清楚會好一點)
the younger people are not in their villages.
# 嗯 好甜吶
Um! So sweet!
# 好啦好啦 等下吃飽啦
Enough, enough. Don't get stuffed.
# 今天又不是甚麼
Today is not any special day.
# 如果是情人節的話
If it were the Valentine's Day today,
# 我就拗點去 今天不是
I would bend down some, and bring back home. But it's not.
# 算啦
Forget it!
# 你看 這個是西瓜哦
Look! This is a watermelon.
# 小紅玉來的
It's a "xiaohongyu" (a local watermelon species).
# 用手指一彈就爆掉了 這個很脆的
A single flick is enough to burst it open. It's really brittle.
# 而且都是農戶用那個機肥種的
And they're grown by the farmers with organic fertiliser.
# 到時候我要 拉一車回去
I'm gonna bring one whole cart of them back home,
# 慢慢吃
and enjoy whenever I like.
# 很靚的
Beautiful!
# 你看 這個粘衣服的哦 如果一去的全身衣服都粘滿的
Look! These things stick onto the clothes. They'll be covering all your clothes once you get inside.
# 想[SIC]人人家種的一樣 長得那麼荿盛
They grow so well as if they're grown by somebody.
# 你看這個桃子 全部熟了哦 都紅了
Look! These peaches, they're all ripe, and all red now.
# 你看這個 摘這個來吃一下
Have a look at this one! Let me pick this one and have a try.
# 誒呦
Eyo!
# 竟然會掉
Why did it fall?
# 這個
This one
# 誒呀 熟啦
Eya! It's ripe now.
# 裡面的熟啦
It's also ripe inside.
# 你看 徒手就可以把它剝開
Look! I can simply crack it open by hands.
# 嗯~
Um~
# 哇 好香哦 它這個是土桃子來的
Wa! It smells so good! This is our local peach here.
# 壞了
Rotten
# 你看下面還有 (註︰這句不明白)
Look! There are more down there.
# 紅的 就這樣子的
They're all red, just like this one.
# 有點毛 毛有點多
There's some fur. It's a bit furry.
# 挑大點的摘
I'm gonna pick the big ones.
# 你看 這個大
Look! This is big!
# 還可以哦
Not bad
# 一樹都是
They're all over the trees.
# 你看 這個李子樹
Look! This is a plum tree.
# 好多哦這上面 地上都掉了一地都是 沒人要
There are a lot. They all fell onto the ground. They're everywhere but nobody picks them.
# 哇
Wa!
# 掉那麼多 樹都不用上
So many have fallen down. I don't even need to climb the tree.
# 紅的
It's red.
# 摔爆啦
It's crushed.
# 你看這種李子
Look! This kind of plums,
# 這種李子很好吃哦 這種李子
this kind of plums is really tasty, this kind of plums.
# 在農村裡面 吃都沒人吃
The people in the villages don't really like them.
# 樹上還有好多
There are still a lot in the tree.
# 你看 這是豬血李哦
Look! This is a "pig blood plum".
# 都沒人吃
But nobody wants them.
# 樹上好多
There are a lot in the tree.
# 袋子又沒帶
But I don't have a bag with me.
# 留點
Leave some,
# 留點路過的人吃
leave some to those who pass by.
# 一個人不要把全部摘掉吧
It's too mean to pick everything for my own self.
# 這是野生的
They're wild plums,
# 沒人 沒人要的
and don't, don't belong to anyone.
# 溜達了一圈 甚麼都沒找到
I've strolled around once, but couldn't find anything special.
# 不次西瓜熟了時候我們再來 西瓜現在還沒熟
Let's come again when the watermelons become ripe. They're not yet ripe.
# 熟了之後我們再來
Let's come again when they're ripe.
# 那邊就一大片都是西瓜
The whole area there are watermelons.
# 都是兄弟家的
They're all my buddy's.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦 回去啦
Alright! The video ends here. Let's head back.